Francis Gevrier Guittard papers, Inclusive: 1811-1960, undated, Bulk: 1900-1940
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
Francis Gevrier Guittard papers
Inclusive: 1811-1960, undated, Bulk: 1900-1940
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
451
Guittard, Francis Gevrier, 1867 - 1950
23 document boxes and 6 oversized boxes.
The Francis Gevrier Guittard papers contain the personal papers of Dr. Francis Gevrier Guittard, a prominent history professor who served Baylor University for much of the early twentieth century.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
Francis Gevrier Guittard was born in New Bedford, Ohio, on 1867 January 7. His father, Dr. Francis Joseph Guittard, had immigrated from France at a young age after he refused to become a Catholic clergyman. The elder Guittard moved to Ohio where he met his wife Lydia Meyers. Young Francis was one of eight children born to the couple. In 1886, Francis was encouraged by his parents to set out for Texas in search of better prospects.
Guittard chose to pursue teaching as his lifelong vocation. He taught briefly in Tyler County, Texas, before he began taking classes at Baylor University. Guittard was ultimately unable to complete a degree there, but in 1897, he moved to Chicago to attend one of the nation’s fastest growing history programs at the University of Chicago. He earned his Bachelor of Arts (1901) and his Master of Arts (1902) degrees at the ages of 34 and 35.
Guittard then returned to Texas in pursuit of academic employment. Baylor University President Samuel Palmer Brooks offered him a position in the history department, and Guittard remained in this position until his death, serving as the Chairman of the department for over forty years.
In 1906, Guittard married Mamie Welhausen. The couple had three children: Francis Gevrier, Jr. (1907), Charles Welhausen (1915), and Clarence Alwin (1917). Charles passed away one year after his birth, but the other two sons survived into adulthood. Mamie Guittard passed away shortly after the birth of Clarence in 1917. Francis remarried in 1920 when he wed Josephine “Mama Josie” Glenn.
Although Francis Guittard had secured his teaching position at a university, he was not satisfied with his level of education. In the 1920s, Guittard took courses at Leeland Stanford University in California, balancing his own schoolwork with his teaching duties. This hard work paid off in 1931, when Guittard, at the age of 64, earned his Ph.D. with his dissertation “Roosevelt and Conservation.”
Dr. Guittard returned to Baylor University and devoted his time and effort to the education of his students. On April 28, 1950, Guittard passed away due to a heart attack. He was survived by his wife Josephine and his two sons, Francis and Clarence.
In 1959, the year following Josephine Guittard’s passing, a fellowship was created by the will of Dr. and Mrs. Francis Guittard. The Guittard Fellowship continues to fund students who are pursuing history at the graduate level.
Scope and Content
The Francis Gevrier Guittard papers range in chronology from 1811 to 1960, beginning with the story of the immigration of Guittard's ancestors. The materials then transition into his own life, beginning with his trek from Ohio to Texas. Guittard's pursuit of education is also well documented. Numerous diaries and notebooks reveal his intellectual development from his time at Baylor University, the University of Chicago, and Leeland Stanford University. The largest series, Series IV. Literary Productions, contains his own coursework, information about his travels, manuscripts prepared for publication, and other such materials.
Arrangement
The Francis Gevrier Guittard papers were fairly organized prior to this processing for this finding aid. The folder titles were, for the most part, helpful in identifying the types of materials in the collection. A corresponding folder inventory was also available.
There were no series level descriptions in the collection. This latest round of processing has relied upon the old level of organization with a few minor changes. There are now eleven series in the Francis Gevrier Guittard Papers: I. Correspondence, II. Legal Documents, III. Financial Documents, IV. Literary Productions, V. Genealogical Materials, VI. Photographic Materials, VII. Artifacts, VIII. Certificates, IX. Scrapbooks, X. Maps, and XI. Classroom Records.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 451. Acquired 0-00-00
Related Resources
Related references
Cagle, Louise Moore. “The Life of Francis Gevrier Guittard.” M.A. thesis, Baylor University, 1951.
“Rites Held Yesterday for Dr. F.G. Guittard.” The Daily Lariat. May 2, 1950. Accessed 2012 December 10.
"Guittard Fellowships Established by Will." Baylor Lariat. February 5, 1959. Accessed 2012 December 11.
Wick, Sharon. "Francis Joseph Guittard." Accessed 2012 December 11.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Guittard, Francis Gevrier, 1867-1950.
Subjects (Organizations)
Baylor University -- History.; Baylor University -- History -- 20th century.
Subjects
Genealogy.; Postcards.; World War, 1914-1918 -- United States.
Genres
Booklets.; Brochures.; Certificates.; Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Contracts.; Correspondence.; Diaries.; Essays.; Financial records.; Manuscripts.; Maps.; Periodicals.; Photographs.; Programs.; Reports.; Research notes.; Scrapbooks.; Speeches.
- Correspondence, 1851-1952, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Average.
  Biography/Profile
  The following series contains personal and business correspondence from Dr. Francis Gevrier Guittard. Letters composed in French, which were primarily letters from Guittard's ancestors, have been designated accordingly. Correspondence exchanged between Dr. Guittard and members of his family, particularly his wife Josephine, have also been set apart. This series is in average to good condition.
  - General: English, 1856-1898 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General: English, 1902-1919 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - General: English, 1920-1923 June (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - General: English, 1923 July-1925 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - General: English, 1926-1927 June (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - General: English, 1927 July-1928 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - General: English, 1929 March-June (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - General: English, 1929 July-August (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - General: English, 1929 September-1931 July (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - General: English, 1932 March-1935 October (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - General: English, 1936-1941 April (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - General: English, 1941 July-1945 August (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - General: English, 1945 November-1946 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - General: English, 1947 February-September (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - General: English, 1947 October-1948 February (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - General: English, 1948 May-1950 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - General: English, 1952, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - General: French, 1851-1864 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - General: French, 1873-1896 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Cards (1 of 2), 1949, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Cards (2 of 2), 1949, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Announcements: General, 1885-1944 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Baylor University: History Department, 1927-1942, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Family, 1900-1926 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Family, 1927-1929 May (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Family, 1929 June-July 15 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Family, 1929 July 27-August 5 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Family, 1929 August 10-23 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Family, 1930 January 16-November 16 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Family, 1930 November 26-1931 February 21 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Family, 1931 March 15-May 16 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Family, 1931 May 22-1932 May 3 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Family, 1932 July 15-1934 February 7 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Family, 1941-1943 August (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Family, 1943 September-1944 May (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Family, 1944 November 15-1947 May 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Family, 1947 June-1951 December (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Family, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Francis and Josephine Guittard, 1916-1923 June 16 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Francis and Josephine Guittard, 1923 June 18-July 5 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Francis and Josephine Guittard, 1923 July 7-18 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Francis and Josephine Guittard, 1923 July 19-30 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Francis and Josephine Guittard, 1923 August 2-1926 June 22 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Francis and Josephine Guittard, 1926 August 28-1927 July 2 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Francis and Josephine Guittard, 1927 July 3-1928 June 12 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Francis and Josephine Guittard, 1928 August 15-1929 June 29 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Francis and Josephine Guittard, 1929 July 1-9 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Francis and Josephine Guittard, 1929 July 12-30 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Francis and Josephine Guittard, 1929 August 1-9 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Francis and Josephine Guittard, 1929 August 12-17 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Francis and Josephine Guittard, 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Francis and Josephine Guittard, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Francis Gevrier Guittard to Samuel Palmer Brooks, 1926 March 22- 1927 May 10 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Guy B. Harrison, Jr. to Francis Gevrier Guittard, 1923-1927 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Invitations: Weddings, 1925-1951 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - John Battle to Francis Gevrier Guittard, 1902 May 22- 1905 March 21 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Mr. and Mrs. A.J. Armstrong to Guittards, 1914, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Mrs. A.P. Cagle, 1951 May 10-16 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Mrs. A.P. Cagle, 1951 May 19-31, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Pat Neff to Francis Gevrier Guittard, 1932 April 7- 1947 March 28 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Samuel Palmer Brooks to Francis Gevrier Guittard, 1902 July 10- 1928 June 9 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - W.R. Poage to Francis Gevrier Guittard, 1940 September 7 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Legal Documents, 1831-1952; 2
  This small series contains legal documents pertaining to Francis and Josephine Guittard. Significant materials include Josephine's passport, Francis' teaching contracts, and a legal brief. The materials are in average condition.
  - General, 1831-1904 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Brief: W. Shropshire vs. James Shaw, circa 1928 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Contracts: Teaching, 1898-1899 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Passport: Josephine Guittard, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Financial Documents, 1868-1941, undated; 3
  General condition: Good.
  The following series consists of financial ledgers, receipts, and rolls collected by Francis Gevrier Guittard. The rolls for Waco public school teachers is a particularly valuable resource for the researcher interested in salary information from the 1930s and 1940s. The materials are in good condition.
  - Ledger: Columbia County Bank, 1896-1902 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Ledger: Estate: George Myers, 1868-1878 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Ledger: Liberty National Bank, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Ledger: Personal, 1902-1917 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Ledger: School Expenses: Francis Gevrier Guittard, 1898-1899 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Ledger: University of Chicago, 1902-1903 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Receipts, 1885-1902 June (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Receipts, 1902 July-1907 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Rolls: Waco Public Schools: Staff, 1940-1941, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Rolls: Waco Public Schools: Teachers, 1936 July 10 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Literary Productions, 1811-1960, undated; 4
  This series is the largest in the collection. It is comprised of Dr. Guittard's collected history books, newspaper clippings, manuscripts that he wrote as a student, notebooks, postcards, and other printed materials. The breadth of this series is a testament to Guittard's passion for history, his travels around the world, and his love of learning. The materials are in average to good condition.
  - Address: Daughters of the Confederacy, 1928 December 3 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Address: Philosophian Society, 1895 February 23 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Address: “Proposed Recognition of Russia”, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Autographs: General, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Biographical Materials: Francis Gevrier Guittard, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Biographical Materials: Francis Joseph Guittard, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Book: A Fortnight in Kent: Gordon Cooper, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Book: Cathedrals of England: John Blair and Joyce Cowley, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Book: Canterbury: Arthur Mee, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Book: Desert of the Lions: Luis Olvera, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Book: Holy Bible: Francis Gevrier Guittard, 1885 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Book: Holy Bible: Francis Gevrier Guittard: Marginalia, 1885 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Book: Holy Bible: French: Francis Gevrier Guittard: Marginalia, 1902 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Book: Holy Bible: German: Tombaugh Family: Marginalia, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Book: Illustrated Guide: Royal Botanical Gardens Kew, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Book: Illustrated Guide to Cambridge: Frank Rutter, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Book: L’Ange Conducteur dans la Dévotion Chrétienne: Gevrier Family, 1811 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Book: Mexican Folklore: Justino Fernandez, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Book: Mexico City: Ruth Poyo, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Book: Pomp and Circumstance: Betty Spencer Shew, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Book: Tasco: Esteban A. de Varona, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Book: Taxco: The Enchanted City: Leslie C. de Figueroa, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Book: The Hermitage: Home of General Andrew, 1931 June 1 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Book: The Sights of Versailles: Pierre Morel, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Book: Venice: Lake Garda and the Dolomites, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Booklet: A Phreno-Organic Chart for Recording Constitutional Conditions and Forces, Mental Developments, and Characteristics: Professor Hertig, 1883 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Booklet: Andrew Johnson, 1937 August (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Booklet: The Peace Palace: The Hague, Netherlands, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Booklet: Warwick Castle, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Brochure: “1952 Guide for France” (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Brochure: “Air France”, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Brochure: “Gateways and Doorways of Charleston”, 1888 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Brochure: “Hatfield House”: Lord David Cecil, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Brochure: “Niagara in Summer and Winter”, 1896 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Brochure: “Shakespeare’s Stratford-Upon-Avon”, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Brochure: “The British Isles”, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Brochure: “Your Tour of Europe”, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Bulletin: National Education Association, 1933 January (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Bulletin: Stanford University: “Abstracts of Dissertations”, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Calling Cards: Baad-Ewing, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Calling Cards: Frescher-Lechner, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Calling Cards: Guittards, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Calling Cards: Levengood-Redman, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Calling Cards: Rich-Whitmer, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Catalog: Masterworks of Five Centuries: Golden Gate International Exposition, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Catalog: Southwestern Academy: Magnolia, Arkansas, 1899-1900 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Catalog: Waco Council Parent-Teacher Association, 1923-1924 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Catalog: Waco Council Parent-Teacher Association, 1924-1925 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Clippings: General, 1925-1935 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Clippings: General, 1936-1949 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Clippings: General, 1950-1952 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Clippings: General, 1957-1959 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Clippings: General (1 of 3), undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Clippings: General (2 of 3), undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Clippings: General (3 of 3), undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Constitution: Farmers State Alliance, 1888 August (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Constitution and By-Laws: Students’ Association: Baylor University, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Diary: Francis Gevrier Guittard, 1883-1925 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Dissertation: “Roosevelt and Conservation”: Francis Gevrier Guittard, 1930 August (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Essay: Student: “History of the American Merchant Marine”: S.R. Smith, 1921 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Essay: Student: “Mormonism and Its Menace to Our Nation”: W.G. Barrett, 1915 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Essay: Student: “The Status of Polygamy in the West”: Burton, 1913 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Essay: “The Development of Nationalism in China Since the Revolution of 1911-1912”: Francis Gevrier Guittard, 1926 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Essay Book: Francis Gevrier Guittard: Baylor University, 1893-1894 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Eulogies: Dr. W.P. Meroney and Judge Jenkins, 1933, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Exam: Baylor University: History, 1941 April (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Exams: Baylor University: Comprehensive (1 of 3), 1938 spring (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Exams: Baylor University: Comprehensive (2 of 3), 1938 spring (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Exams: Baylor University: Comprehensive (3 of 3), 1938 spring (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Exams: Baylor University: English and Psychology, 1938 July (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Exams: Economics, 1905-1914, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Exams: History, 1907-1909 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Exams: History, 1914-1938 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Exams: History, 1939, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Exams: Princeton University: History, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Guide: “How to See the Islands and Palazzo Borromeo”: A. La Spina, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Guide: Illustrations: Chicago, Illinois, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Guide: Photographs: Canterbury, England, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Guide: Texas Centennial Celebration, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Guide: Two Weeks in Mexico”: Helga Kuegelgen, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Handbook: “Rules, Regulations, and Policies of the Waco Public Schools”, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Manuscript: “Administrative Reforms of Maria Theresa”, 1901 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Manuscript: “Autobiography of Frank G. Guittard”, 1900 July 16 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Manuscript: “Commerce and Industry of Florence in the 14th and 15th Centuries”, 1910 March 28 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Manuscript: “David the Type of Christ in Service and Suffering”, 1903 October 11 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Manuscript: “Description of a Landscape”, 1900 September 10 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Manuscript: Dissertation: “Roosevelt and Conservation”: Francis Gevrier Guittard (1 of 2), 1930 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript: Dissertation: “Roosevelt and Conservation”: Francis Gevrier Guittard (2 of 2), 1930 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript: “Four Minute Speech on the Seventy-Five Million Campaign”, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Manuscript: “Has the Sun an Atmosphere?”, 1900 August 27 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Manuscript: “Hawaii: People and History”, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Manuscript: “Heine’s External Nature Sense”, 1901 March 19 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Manuscript: “Higher Education in Latin America”, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Manuscript: James Blaine, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Manuscript: “John Keats’ Hyperion ”, 1902 May 28 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Manuscript: “John Weaver, Mayor of Philadelphia”, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Manuscript: “Lecture on the European War”, circa 1916 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Manuscript: “Luther’s Attitudes toward the Peasants”, 1901 July 8 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Manuscript: “National Safeguards”, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Manuscript: “Our National Safeguards”, 1900 August 13 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Manuscript: Prayer Meeting: Students’ Association, 1905 October 27 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Manuscript: “Providences in History”, 1911 February 28 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Manuscript: “Reborned in Texas”, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript: “Resolved that Co-education in Our Colleges and Universities is the Better System for the Education of the Sexes”, 1900 September 3 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript: “Sketch of the Life of John A. Johnson”, 1924 July 2 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Manuscript: “Specialization in College Work”, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Manuscript: “The American Flag”, circa 1917 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Manuscript: “The Camp Meeting at Magnesia Springs”, 1900 July 23 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Manuscript: “The Case of the Douglas”, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Manuscript: “The Case of the Douglas in Relation to the Right of Search Controversy”, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Manuscript: “The Emancipation of Slavery in Brazil”, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Manuscript: “The Incorporation of Trade Unions”, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Manuscript: “The Islands of Hawaii: The Islands and Their Products”, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Manuscript: “The Labor Movement in America”, 1905 July 7 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Manuscript: “The Origin of the Republican Party”, 1901 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Manuscript: “The Situation in China”, 1906 March 12 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Manuscript: “The Telescopic Appearance of the Moon”, 1900 August 6 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Manuscript: “The Wright Brothers”, 1909 May 24 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Manuscripts: General, 1900 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Manuscripts: “Colbert’s Internal Improvement Policy,” “Dickens’ David Copperfield,” and “Jefferson Davis”, 1900-1901, undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Manuscripts: “Comparison of Wordsworth, Scott, and Byron” and “Critique of Wordsworth’s Ode to Duty ”, undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Manuscripts: “Dr. Burleson of Baylor University” and “Incident at Baylor Chapel”, 1900, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Manuscripts: Erysipelas, undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Manuscripts: Machiavelli, 1901, 1924 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Manuscripts: Radio Addresses, undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Notebook: Baylor University: Directions for Senior Rehearsal, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Notebook: English History (1 of 4), undated (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Notebook: English History (2 of 4), undated (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Notebook: English History (3 of 4), undated (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Notebook: English History (4 of 4), undated (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Notebook: English History 104 (1 of 3), undated (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Notebook: English History 104 (2 of 3), undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Notebook: English History 104 (3 of 3), undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Notebook: Favorite Quotes, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Notebook: History 2 (1 of 5), undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Notebook: History 2 (2 of 5), undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Notebook: History 2 (3 of 5), undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Notebook: History 2 (4 of 5), undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Notebook: History 2 (5 of 5), undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Notebook: History 105 (1 of 6), undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Notebook: History 105 (2 of 6), undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Notebook: History 105 (3 of 6), undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Notebook: History 105 (4 of 6), undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Notebook: History 105 (5 of 6), undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Notebook: History 105 (6 of 6), undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Notebook: History 203 (1 of 6), undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Notebook: History 203 (2 of 6), undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Notebook: History 203 (3 of 6), undated (Box 10, Folder 17)